So far in this lesson,
到目前为止
we've looked at a particular policy Pi,
我们查看了一个特定的策略 π
and calculated its corresponding value function.
计算了它对应的值函数
In the quiz, you calculated the value function
在这道练习中 你计算了
corresponding to a different policy which we denoted by Pi-Prime.
另一个不同策略的值函数 我们将此策略表示为 π′
And if you look at each of these value functions,
如果你观察每个值函数
you may notice a pattern or trend.
可能会发现某种规律
Take the time now to compare them and pause the video if you like.
请花时间对比下这些函数 可以暂停视频
So in reality, there are probably a great number of patterns in these numbers,
在现实中 这些数字可能有很多规律
but the most relevant trend to us now is that when we look at
但是现在对我们来说最重要的规律是
any state in particular and compare the two value functions,
当我们查看任何状态并对比这两个值函数时
the value function for a Pi-Prime is always bigger
π′ 的值函数始终大于或等于
than or equal to the value function for policy Pi.
策略 π 的值函数
For instance, 2 is greater than negative 6,
例如 2 大于 -6
3 is greater than negative 5,
3 大于 -5
4 is greater than negative 4,
4 大于 -4
and 1 is equal to 1.
1 等于 1
So this says, for any state in the environment,
也就是说 对于环境中的任何状态
it's better to follow policy Pi-prime, right?
遵守策略 π′ 都效果更好 对吧
Because no matter where the agent starts in the grid world,
因为无论智能体从哪个网格世界开始
they expected discounted return is larger,
预期折扣回报都更大
and remember that the goal of the agent is to maximize return.
注意 智能体的目标是最大化回报
So, a greater expected return makes for a better policy.
因此更好的预期回报表明策略更好
This motivates an important definition.
这就引出了一个重要的定义
By definition, we say that a policy Pi-Prime is better than or equal to
根据定义 如果策略 π′ 的所有状态的状态值函数
a policy Pi if it's state-value function is greater
大于或等于策略 π 的值函数
than or equal to that of policy Pi for all states.
则策略 π′ 的效果比策略 π 好或效果相同
And so there are a couple of important things to note about this definition.
对于此定义 需要注意几个事项
The first is that if you take any two policies,
首先是对于任何两个策略
it's not necessarily the case that you're going to be able to decide which is better.
并不一定能够判断哪个更好
In other words, it's possible that they can't be compared.
换句话说 它们可能无法比较
But said, there will always be
但是 始终至少有一个策略
at least one policy that's better than or equal to all other policies.
比所有其他策略效果更好或效果一样
We call this policy an optimal policy,
我们将此策略称之为最优策略
and it's guaranteed to exist but it may not be unique,
肯定存在这种策略 但是不一定是唯一的
and it's important to note that an optimal policy is what the agent is searching for.
注意 最优策略正是智能体寻找的策略
It's the solution to the MDP and the best strategy to accomplish it's goal.
它是 MDP 的解决方案和实现目标的最佳策略
Finally, all optimal policies have the same value function which we denote by Vstar.
最后 所有最优策略都具有相同的值函数 表示为 v*
You might be wondering why it's not written,
你可能会疑问
V sub Pi star.
为何不写成 Vπ*
The answer is by convention,
答案是这是惯例
and probably because it just looks nicer this way.
并且可能看起来更美观
On that note, it turns out that the policy from the quiz is actually an optimal policy.
实际上练习中的策略是最优策略
This is because if you compare it to the value function for any other possible policy,
因为如果你将其与任何其他潜在策略的值函数相比
it's value function is always at least as big,
它的值函数将始终大于或等于比较的值
but it's not the only optimal policy.
但是它不是唯一的最优策略
For instance, here's another policy that has the same value function,
例如 这是另一个值函数相同的策略
and you might be wondering at this point how I found these optimal policies.
此刻 你可能会疑问 我是如何得出这些最优策略的
Well, this example was simple enough that it was possible to make
这个示例很简单 通过观察动态特性
an educated guess just by staring at the dynamics,
也许就能猜出结果
but this will often not be the case as many of
但是通常并非这样
the MDPs will look at will be far more complicated.
因为很多 MDP 看起来复杂得多
So how might we determine an optimal policy for a much more complicated MDP?
那么 我们如何得出更加复杂的 MDP 的最优策略？
To answer this question,
为了回答这一问题
we'll need to define another type of value function.
我们需要定义另一种类型的值函数